Jia-Cheng "JC" Gong

41 Luscombe St. Hamilton, ON

jia-cheng.gong@mohawkcollege.ca / jgong117398@gmail.com / 647-617-8257

Profile

- Enthusiast of computer hardware, maintained & repaired hundreds of different technologies
- Excellent at handling difficult tasks in-&-out of my profession, and solve with focus on quality
- Excellent of solving very difficult problems, meanwhile being user-friendly
- Very experienced at building engaging user guides, tutorials, documents, charts, test-plans

Technical Skills

CLI Tools / Scripts: Git/GitHub, CMD-Batch, PowerShell w/ WinForms, Bash/Terminal, x264/5, ffmpeg

Coding: Java, PHP, C# (.Net), JavaScript, React, Python

Server Mgmt.: SQL, Email, (S)FTP, Radius, DHCP, NTP, HTTP(S) with LAMP, WAMP

Documentation: HTML-CSS-JS, Microsoft Word, Excel, Markdown, LaTex-Math

Ent. Networking: Cisco CCNA & CCNP (VLAN, HSRP, STP, EtherChannel, Subnetting, etc.)

Org. Security: Network security, Operating System security, Software Forensics

Other Developing: Software QA & Testing, System Analysis & Design, Database Management Multimedia Tools: Premiere, Photoshop, After Effects, Audition, OBS, FL-Studio, YouTube studio Multimedia Skills: Video-Audio-Image Editing, Video encoding, Audio Analysis, Color Correction Cloud-Computing, Active Directory, GitHub Actions, Project Management,

Virtualization, Docker

Education

Software Development - Computer Systems Technology

2023-Present

Mohawk College - Hamilton, ON (GPA 82.9%, 3-year advanced diploma)

Network Engineering & Security Analyst - Computer Systems Technology

2017-2023

Mohawk College - Hamilton, ON (GPA 80.2%, 3-year advanced diploma)

Dec 2021

Network Systems - Computer Systems Technology

Mohawk College - Hamilton, ON (GPA 79.2%, diploma)

Projects

Networking April 2021

- Managed & troubleshooted network devices for optimal functionality
- Finished with 50+ Cisco CCNA scenario labs & kept notes for later use

Emergency Response Plan Writing

March 2021

- Made a 12-page document describing how a fictitious company would run under pandemic
- Helped to coordinate workload in a group of 5 people

Network Infrastructure Design

December 2020

- Designed an all-around enterprise network for a fictitious company
- Proactively contacted passive group members, and persuaded them to continue

Restaurant Menu Design

November 2019

Designed and composed a 6-page restaurant menu with Photoshop

• Performed image color correction, image ID tagging on 50+ dishes, which is significantly better quality than "text only" menus

References

• Mat Ferris (IT Operations, email preferred)

linkedin.com/in/mat-ferris-0707a924

• Mr. Qian (Restaurant director & hire)

Work Experience

Computer Support / Desk Support Specialist (Benning Financial Corp.) Sept 2021-Dec 31 2021

- Managing and troubleshooting staffs' computer via remote platforms (Desktop Central, TeamViewer, Sophos Central)
- Configure new laptop to join corp. domain & setup software environment for new hires
- Pushed the task to upgrade staff's computer to near finish with very good user satisfaction
- Automized some computer configurations via PowerShell & CMD scripts

Field Network Technician (Bell / Bell Technical Solutions)

June 2022-Sep 2022

- Performed hundreds of copper network installation & repairs spanning all the way from Bell central office to residential homes
- Operated Bell truck, power tools, 26ft ladder, mobile cable tester, safety equipment, work phone
- Performed includes cable testing, jumper configuration, pole/strand climbing to reach terminal, run service wire from terminal to houses, install demarcation, drilling, inside wire installation and modem setup, always left with very satisfied customers
- In special cases, manually configured Lucent Stinger DSL & Alcatel 7330's software, satisfied
 angry customer, survived very steep learning curve, high load & tight schedules in busy season
 while maintaining work quality (which caused 80% of new hires to quit), worked out impossible
 tasks that requires high patience and skill

Fast Food Cook (August 8 – Stoney Creek)

June 2021-Aug 2021

- Task involves fast-paced teamwork between restaurant server & other cooks
- Work under pressure when food order stacks up in high demand hours

Volunteer Experience

Voukoder Plugin (Opensource project, GitHub)

April 2022-Present

Contributed multiple AVC & HEVC encoder configurations in JSON format

Hamilton Victory Gardens (St. Helens division)

- · Participated in farming several times as a volunteer
- Co-operated with many people in different ages
- Maintained & harvested vegetables throughout summer in a large farm

Enbridge (Ride to Conquer Cancer)

McMaster University, Hamilton, 2016 & 17

- participated a sport event as a volunteer member and leader
- established large temporary tents, served food & chatted with management during day 1-2